Julius Regalado

www.juliusregalado.com linkedin.com/in/juliusregalado Varsey City, NJ | P (201) 275-5275 | @ jreg03@outlook.com

SUMMARY

Problem solving and analyzation skills along with web development expertise that covers a multitude of programming languages, frameworks and libraries is what I bring to the table, with an understanding in UX and UI design to prototyping and translating mockups into working scalable code, combined with artistic creativity in building intricate web applications.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Web Application Development • Object Oriented Programming • Strategic Thinking

Javascript • React • Redux • Bootstrap • HTML • CSS • GSAP • Java • Spring Boot • Node Js • Express • Sass • Postgres

Responsive design and development • MVC • Agile Best Practices

EXPERIENCE

Case Agency | New York, NY

Front-end Web Developer Intern

Sept 2018 - Dec 2018

- Translated UI/UX design into working HTML, CSS/SCSS and JS code.
- Built reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Collaborated with the team leader to ensure optimization of the application for efficiency and scalability.

General Assembly | New York, NY

Software Engineering Training

May 2018 - June 2018

- The Software Engineering Career Accelerator, developed by General Assembly, is a 5-week immersive experience that teaches junior web developers the skills needed to be a full stack engineer.
- Graduates of this training will be experienced in technical areas like full stack java, front-end frameworks like React
 and/or Angular, test-driven development, devOps, distributed services with AWS, and building/deploying Spring
 microservices. In addition, this training also covers software lifecycle and agile best practices.

General Assembly | New York, NY

Web Development Immersive

Jan 2018 - Apr 2018

- Led the design and development process of a Full Pet Adoption Web Application by working with a team of 3 other web developers using technologies such as Javascript, React, Node.js, Express framework and Postgres.
- Developed a full crud application for managing recipes through full agile methodology and writing code full-stack.

United States Navy — Ship's Serviceman 3rd Class

SEPTEMBER 2008 - SEPTEMBER 2010 | VFA 115 | Naval Air Station Atsugi Japan

 Collected, organized and handled information such as flight logs and flight schedules into computer databases for effective record keeping.

FEBRUARY 2005 - SEPTEMBER 2008 | USS Kitty Hawk | Yokosuka Japan

Responsible for managing and operating shipboard retail and service activities

EDUCATION

General Assembly, New York, NY Web Development and Software Engineering JANUARY 2018 - JUNE 2018

Culinary Tech Center, New York, NY Commercial Cookery and Hospitality Management

MARCH 2014 - DECEMBER 2016

Asia Pacific College, Makati City, Philippines Bachelor of Arts in Multimedia Arts (Undergrad) JUNE 2010 - APRIL 2012